# James Ryan

james4165@hotmail.com Mobile Ph: 0430 710 408 jamesryan.azurewebsites.net

I have 5 years of programming experience including over a year of web programming. My education is as a Civil Engineer though I am very interested in making a career change to web development.

Have a look at my portfolio for examples of my experience: <a href="mailto:jamesryan.azurewebsites.net">jamesryan.azurewebsites.net</a>

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

2009 to 2013 Bachelor of Engineering majoring in Civil and Construction

Queensland University of Technology

2005 to 2006 **Diploma of Mechanical Engineering** 

Moreton Institute of TAFE

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

2013 to Nov 2015 **Graduate Engineer (Full-Time)** 

**Real Serious Games** 

# Key Accomplishments:

- Use of Microsoft Excel for manipulating construction schedule data and other data
- Providing basic mockup drawings for modifications to 3D Models
- QA of software
- Programming of various tools used in the office (C#, WPF and VBA) and communicating with programmers
- General administration duties
- Communicating construction drawings to 3D modelers

2011 to 2013 Trainee Structural Engineer (Full-Time)

**NBR** Australia

### Key Accomplishments:

- Carried out structural design of cold-formed steel portal frame buildings and various types of residential buildings.
- Structural drafting of various commercial and industrial portal frame buildings and residential homes and associated detail drawings
- Developed in-house structural engineering software used for analysing loads and calculating bracing, member and connection requirements for portal frame buildings
- Development of 3D portal frame model and load generation software in Excel/VBA using Multiframe Automation.
- Used many different Australian Standards and product manuals
- Other duties such as general administration and document handling/organisation

Resume: James Ryan

### 2008 to 2012

### **Draftsman (Part-Time)**

Etto Designs and Drafting

# Key Accomplishments:

- Assisted with drafting work on all types of residential dwellings
- Mostly architectural drafting of floor plans, elevations, sections, site plans
- Extensively used AutoCad 2007
- Some structural drafting such as bracing and slab plans

# **Extra Curricular Achievements**

- Winner of 2011 Baulderstone National Icons design competition
  - 1st place out of over 150 entries nation wide
  - Winning entry consisted of conceptual redesign of the Story Bridge and 700 word report
- Designed and published two Android applications on Google Play
  - "EasyBeam" a structural engineering application
  - "Where in the World", a Google map and streetview based guessing game

# **Programming Skills**

I have been programming on my own personal projects and at previous workplaces for almost 5 years and have experience with :

- C# and WPF
- Java for Android
- Node.js, html, sass/css, javascript and some SQL Server, Azure Websites, Angular.js and Backbone.js. Also some PHP and Laravel
- Very proficient with Microsoft Excel and VBA, and knowledge of Microsoft Word and other general office related computer skills

### Interests

- Computers & Programming(Web, C#, VBA)
- Sharemarket

- Video Games
- Making guitar/electronic songs

### **REFEREES**

**Dr Greg Darcy** 

**Rod Etto** 

NBR Australia

**Etto Designs and Drafting** 

Ph: 0421 671 454

Ph: 0411 564 529

# **Professor Tommy Chan**

Queensland University of Technology (QUT) tommy.chan@qut.edu.au

Resume: James Ryan